pinoytechsaga.blogspot.com 2019-07-25

# Privacy Policy | PinoyTechSaga

**Introduction**

PinoyTechSaga blog recognizes that your privacy is very important and we take it seriously. This Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy") describes our policies and procedures on the collection, use, disclosure, and sharing of your personal information or personal data when you use our blog. PinoyTechSaga seeks to comply with all laws and regulations that apply to the gathering and use of personal information, including but not limited to US privacy laws and the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). As used in this policy, "we" and "us" includes PinoyTechSaga and our staff.

**Information We May Collect**

_Technical Information_

Non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, and to our blog itself respectively. To explain further, when you visit PinoyTechSaga blog, certain non-personally identifiable and aggregate information is collected. This data was gathered by Blogger, Google Analytics, Google AdSense and Disqus which helps us to analyze and improve the usefulness of the information we provide on the blog. In order for you to make an informed decision about whether to use and navigate our blog, we are providing you with the following information about how we collect and use non-personally identifiable and aggregate information. By "non-personally identifiable information", we mean information that does not identify you personally, but provides us with anonymous "usage data", such as the number of unique visitors we receive, what pages are visited most often and the navigation preferences and characteristics of our visitors. This data gathering was processed with the use of cookies. To see more information about cookies, you may refer to the Cookies Policy section below.

_Personal Information_

When commenting or contacting on our blog, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address or other details to help you with your experience.

Comments: When visitors leave comments on the blog, we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor's IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection. An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Disqus service to see if you are using it. The Disqus service privacy policy is available here: https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/disqus-privacy-policy. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

Contact form: When someone contacts us, the user needs to provide his/her name and email address. We use these data to contact him/her further. We don't use this data for marketing purpose.

Subscription form: We collect the user's data while someone joins our newsletter powered by Google FeedBurner. The data is fully protected. Google FeedBurner privacy policy is available here https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/.

_Further Information on Personal Data_

Our blog is not aimed at children under 13 years. Users declare to be of age according to the legislation applicable to them. Minors may use this blog only with the assistance of a parent or guardian. Under no circumstances under the age of 13 can use this blog.

**How We May Use and Disclose Your Information**

_Use by PinoyTechSaga_

PinoyTechSaga uses your information as described above, and to customize your experience on the blog and to facilitate our interactions with you, if any. We do not typically take note of your information; the information is mainly stored on or by our servers, tools, and systems, as described above. In some cases, the applications or user interfaces you encounter while on our blog is managed by third parties, who may require that you provide your personal information and who have assured us of their compliance with applicable laws.

_No Sale or Leasing of Your Information_

Except as described in this privacy policy, we will not disclose your personal information to third parties without your consent. We will not sell or lease your personal information to any third party. We may disclose aggregate demographic and statistical information with our business partners; this information is not specific to the identification of you as an individual.

**Cookies Policy**

Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site's or service provider's systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. PinoyTechSaga blog (service provided by Blogger, Google Inc.) and other third-party tools used in the blog like Google Analytics with with anonymized IP, Google AdSense and Disqus uses cookies to compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that the blog can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. 

You may opt not to receive cookies by not accepting them or disabling them on your browser configuration. However, by doing this, you may not be able to fully utilize the features of our blog.

**Advertisements**

PinoyTechSaga uses third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit this blog. These companies may use information about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. Moreover, companies may place cookies to ensure that advertisements are optimized in a way that they are distributed in a proper sequence wherein the same ads are not shown on a single browser repeatedly. 

  * Third party vendors, including Google AdSense, use cookies to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to your website.
  * Google AdSense's use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to you based on your visit to our blog and/or other sites on the Internet.
  * You may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting the [Google ads preference manager](https://www.google.com/settings/ads). Alternatively, you can opt out of a third-party vendor's use of cookies for interest-based advertising by visiting [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) website. It lists networks that offer opt-out cookies and lets you opt out of networks you select.

**Third Party Links**

This blog contains links to other sites. Please note that PinoyTechSaga is not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites. The blog admin encourage the users to be aware when they leave the blog and read the terms of the privacy of each and every website collecting personally identifiable information. This statement applies only to confidential information collected by this website.

**Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

By visiting this Blog, you signify your acceptance to PinoyTechSaga's Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not visit the Blog. PinoyTechSaga reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If the blog admin makes material changes to this policy, he will also revise the "last updated" date at the bottom of this Privacy Policy. Your continued visit to this Blog will signify your approval of the changes to PinoyTechSaga's Privacy Policy.

**Questions and Concerns**

If you have any questions or concerns about the privacy policy, please contact me via email to: pinoytechsaga[at]gmail.com

_**Last Updated : May 25, 2018**_
